# SUZANNE THORNTON, PHD

Philadelphia, PA | 863-370-9389 | thornton.suzy@gmail.com | dr-suz.github.io

#### SUMMARY

A statistical researcher with over four years of college-level teaching experience who is eager to transition into a profession of practice. Proven leadership skills both within and outside of academia. Strong statistical theorist and programmer with excellent communication abilities. A longer CV is available at: https://dr-suz.github.io/portfolio.html

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# National Institute of Standards and Technology PREP Postdoctoral Assistant George Washington University

Jan 2024 – Present

Washington D.C.

Publication in progress: A Bayesian Solution to Non-standard Measurement Error in Linear Regression

### **Assistant professor of statistics**

Sept 2020 – Dec 2023

Swarthmore College Swarthmore, PA

- Published two original technical papers for a statistics journal and a philosophy of science journal.
- Published three chapters for two separate statistics books.

### Special government employee

Aug 2022 – Dec 2023

US Census Bureau National Advisory Committee on Racial, Ethnic, and Other Populations

Washington, D.C.

 Advocated for careful consideration of the collection and analysis of categorical data and for ethical data collection and analysis practices.

## Visiting assistant professor of statistics

Oct 2019 - Aug 2020

Swarthmore College

Swarthmore, PA

 Published several non-technical statistical papers in Significance Magazine and AMSTAT News regarding inclusion of LGBT+ populations in statistics and data science.

#### Statistical consultant

Sept 2016 - Aug 2019

Office of Statistical Consulting, Rutgers University

New Brunswick, NJ

- Published "Development and validation of a predictive model of drug-resistant genetic generalized epilepsy" in Neurology as a result of work with a client at Robert Wood Johnson Hospital.
- Published "Exact inference on the random-effects model for meta-analyses with few studies" in *Biometrics* while working with several consulting clients.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey

Oct 2019

Doctor of Philosophy in Statistics and Biostatistics

New Brunswick, NJ

Thesis: Advanced computing methods for statistical inference

# University of Florida

May 2014

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics and in Statistics

Gainesville, FL

Thesis: Geometric ergodicity of Gibbs sampler for a hierarchical random effects model: Re-explained

#### STATISTICAL EXPERTISE

<ul><li>Bayesian</li><li>Frequentist</li><li>Meta-analysis</li><li>Categorical data</li><li>Cross validation</li></ul>	<ul> <li>Bootstrap</li> <li>Markov chain Monte Carlo</li> <li>Gibbs sampling</li> <li>Time series</li> <li>Measurement error models</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Generalized linear models (including multivariate, logistic, and random effects models)</li> </ul>
<ul> <li>Cross validation</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Measurement error models</li> </ul>	

#### **PROGRAMMING**

$-R^1$	- SAS/STAT <sup>2</sup>	<ul> <li>Parallel computing<sup>2</sup></li> </ul>
<ul> <li>RMarkdown<sup>1</sup></li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Stan<sup>2</sup></li> </ul>	

# **TOOLS AND SOFTWARE**

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>1</sup>Expert

Command Line/Linux<sup>2</sup>SQL<sup>3</sup>

Tableau<sup>3</sup>Python<sup>3</sup>

MS Office<sup>1</sup>

**OTHER** 

 $\begin{array}{ll} - & \mathsf{LateX}^1 \\ - & \mathsf{Git}^2 \end{array}$ 

Statistical modeling<sup>1</sup>
 Data visualization/analysis<sup>1</sup>

Academic writing<sup>1</sup>
 Non-technical writing<sup>1</sup>

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>2</sup>Proficient

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>3</sup>Advanced beginner